Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Colin Dawkins Papers, 1776-1986 RL.00679
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oral Interviews Series, 1979-1980
  - Transcripts Subseries, 1977, 1979-1980
    - Subject Index, 1979, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Audio Subseries, 1976, 1979
    Consists of a recording tape and cassette tapes of Dawkins's notes and interviews he conducted for his book.
    Tapes are arranged alphabetically.
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Entire subseries is RESTRICTED until written permission received from interviewee or their descendents.
    - Adams, Taylor, 7 Jun., 13 July 1979, 2 tapes (Box 19)
    - Connell, Louise, 22 Jun., 12 July 1979, 2 tapes (Box 19)
    - D'Aloise, Lawrence, 20 June 1979, 2 tapes (Box 19)
    - Elton, Wallace, 1 Aug. 1979 (Box 19)
    - Flower, Henry, 20 July, 16 Oct, 1979, 3 tapes (Box 19)
    - Hamilton Russell, Timothy, 30 Oct. 1979 (Box 19)
    - Hardy, Gelston, 18-20 Sept. 1979, 4 tapes (Box 19)
    - Hinks, Kennett, 12 Sept. 1979, 2 tapes (Box 19)
    - King, Peggy, 19 Oct. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Kohl, Howard, 8 Nov. 1979 see Sam Meek 8 Nov. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Lanigan, Denis, 19 Oct. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Lord, Walter, 13 Oct. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Meek, Sam 8, 10 Nov. 1979, 3 tapes (Box 20)
    - Moloney, Ted, 13 Nov. 1979 see Mygatt, Phil, 13 Nov. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Monsarrat, John, 6 Aug 1979, 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Mygatt, Phil and Ted Moloney, 13 Nov. 1979, 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Olson, Sidney, 19 July, 28 Aug. 1979, 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Reese, Florence, 2 Aug. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Strouse, Norman, 23 Oct. 1979 (Box 20)
    - Taylor, Winfield, 20 June, 16 July, 1979, 2 tapes (Box 21)
    - Tempest, Margaret, 9 Aug. 1979, 2 tapes (Box 21)
    - Thompson, Mrs. W. Roosevelt, (J. Walter Thompson's daughter-in-law), 19 Mar. 1979 (Box 21)
    - Wilson, Edward G., 24 Oct. 1979, 2 tapes (Box 21)
    - Luncheon Meeting: Dawkins, Sharon Gordon, Ginny Bahr, Gene Scarito, Emma Paggioli, and Mary Ellen Evan, 1979, Oct. 17, 7.5 lps recording tape (Box 21)
    - Notes: Howard Henderson Albums, 4 tapes (Box 21)
    - Notes: On Interviews [ Flower, Kohl, Wilson], 3 tapes (Box 21)
    - Notes: Miscellaneous (Box 21)
- Writings Series, 1927-1986, undated (bulk 1981-1986)
  Contains several drafts of sections and sidebars for Dawkins's book. Also has two smaller drafts of manuscripts Dawkins wrote using the materials found in this collection.
  These drafts were never published and remain CLOSED except to the members of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
  - Drafts for Sections in Dawkins's book and a capsule history of JWT, undated (Box 15)
  - Sidebars for Dawkins's book, 1927-1980 and undated (Box 15)
  - Ain't It Hell On A Windy Day, 1981, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Adventures in the Ad Game by Colin Campbell Dawkins, 1986 and undated (Box 22)
  - A Very Interesting Company in a Very Interesting Business, undated, 2 folders (Box 22)
- Oversize Material
  - Officers and Staff (Box 23)
    - Carroll, Carroll, 1965, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Johnston, Don, 1981, April 13 (Box 23)
    - King, Peggy, undated (Box 23)
    - Meek, Sam, 1968, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Olson, Sidney, 1970 (Box 23)
    - Resor, Helen, her sister, Therese Lansdowne Duble, 1920, 1973 (Box 23)
    - Resor, Helen and Stanley, 1951 (Box 23)
    - Resor, Stanley, 1950-1951, 1956, 1962, 1980 and undated (Box 23)
    - Thompson, James Walter, 1968 (Box 23)
    - Woodell, Shirley, 1947, 1958, 1960 (Box 23)
    - Young, James Webb, 1959, 1973 (Box 23)
  - Clients
    - Ford, 1953, 1957, 1959-1960, 1966, 1969 and undated (Box 23)
    - Lever Brothers, undated (Box 23)
  - Alphabetical Files
    - Agency Rankings, 1979-1980 (Box 23)
    - Advertisements, 1912, 1929 and undated (Box 23)
    - Advertising History, 1776, 1970, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Batten, Barton, Durstine, Osborn, Company History, 1974 (Box 23)
    - Broadcast Advertising: Radio, 1937 (Box 23)
    - Broadcast Advertising: Television, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Competitive Advertising Agencies, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Dawkins's Chronological Research Notes, 1970 (Box 23)
    - Does it pay to advertise, 1924, April-May (Box 23)
    - Expenditure Data, 1957 (Box 23)
    - JWT: Advertising Billings, undated (Box 23)
    - JWT Historical Project, 1984 and undated (Box 23)
    - JWT: Some Basic Roots of the J. Walter Thompson Company, undated (Box 23)
    - Lord & Thomas, Lasker, Foote, Cone & Belding, 1965, 1973, 1976 (Box 23)
    - N.W. Ayer, 1976 (Box 23)
    - Offices: Hollywood, 1959 (Box 23)
    - Offices: London, 1985; Round the Square, 1978-1979 (Box 23)
    - Offices: Los Angeles, 1959 (Box 23)
    - Offices: New York, 1980 (Box 23)
    - Quotations and Anecdotes about the Advertising Industry, 1982, 1984 and undated (Box 23)
    - Townsend & Townsend, advertising evaluations company, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Advertisements Series
    - Officers and Staff: (Folder 1)
      - Olson, Sid: House Advertisement, 1970 (Box 23)
      - Resor, Helen and Stanley, J. B. Williams Co., 1951 (Box 23)
      - Resor, Stanley: J. B. Williams Co., 1950-1951 (Box 23)
    - Clients:
      - Ford:
        - 1953 (Box 23)
        - Company, 1957, 1959-1960 (Box 23)
        - Mexico, 1972 (Box 23)
        - Pinto, undated (Box 23)
    - Alphabetical Files:
      - Advertisements:
        - Ballantine Beer, undated (Box 23)
        - Chesebrough-Pond's, undated (Box 23)
        - Procer & Gamble, Crisco, 1912 (Box 23)
        - Simmon's Co., 1929 (Box 23)
      - House Advertisements: 1946-1948, 1961, 1984 (Box 23)
    - Dawkins's Advertisement Portfolio (Folder 2)
      - Newspaper Advertisements:
        - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1958 (Box 23)
        - Dr. West's, 1955 (Box 23)
        - Farrell Lines, 1952 (Box 23)
        - Group Hospitalization, Inc., 1958 (Box 23)
        - Kraft Television Theatre, A Night to Remember, 1956 (Box 23)
        - Norteastern New York Medical Service, Inc., ca. 1958 (Box 23)
        - Parker Pen Co., 1950 (London) (Box 23)
        - Personna, 1950-1951 (London) (Box 23)
        - Sanpic, 1950 (London) (Box 23)
        - Thompson House Ads, 1958 (Box 23)
        - United Medical Service, Inc, 1957-1958 (Box 23)
      - Magazine Advertisements: (Folder 3)
        - Barrett Co., undated (Canada) (Box 23)
        - DE-FLY-ER of Canada, undated (Box 23)
        - Fleischmann, 1949 (Box 23)
        - Ford:
          - 1958-1959, 1965 (Box 23)
          - Company, 1955-1960, 1962 (Box 23)
          - Galaxie, 1962 (Mexico) (Box 23)
          - Industrial trucks, 1956, 1959 (Box 23)
          - Mustang, 1964, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Dawkins's Advertisement Portfolio
      - Magazine Advertisements:
        - Irving Trust Co., 1951 (Box 23)
        - J. B. Williams, 1951, undated (Box 23)
        - Mobil Oil, 1955 (Mexico) (Box 23)
        - Mosler Safe Co., undated (Box 23)
        - Pan American, 1950 (London), 1953 (Box 23)
        - Polyrein Corporation, undated (Canada) (Box 23)
        - Reckitt & Colman Ltd, 1950 (London) (Box 23)
        - Thompson House Ads, 1956-1959 (Box 23)
        - Western Union, 1949 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous Oversize Material (Oversize-folder 1-3)